SPARSH NAGPAL

A self-motivated Computer Engineering undergraduate student with an advanced analytical & creative mindset having a strong link in theoretical and practical approach gained from my courses, research and internship experiences. Along with proficient technical skills, I also possess excellent leadership and management qualities making me a quintessential candidate.

Mumbai, India

9833747258

Osparsh2@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/sparshnagpal https://github.com/Osparsh2

Personal Website:

http://tinyurl.com/sparshnagpal

EDUCATION

Thadomal Shahani Engineering College (University of Mumbai) Mumbai — Bachelor's of Engineering in Computer Science

August 2018 - June 2022 (Expected)

CGPA - 8.83/10 (based on 5 semesters results)

Pace Junior College, Mumbai — High School

April 2016 - March 2018

12th Boards - 83.7%

Pawar Public School, Mumbai — School

April 2014 - March 2016

10th Boards - 96.6%

EXPERIENCE

Friends For Inclusion, remote— NLP Programming and Deep Learning Intern

March 2021 - Present

Modelling the backend of India's first efficient Indian Sign Language translation application using various NLP functionalities from cleaning to implying Named Entity Recognition.

The Sparks Foundation, remote — Computer Vision and IoT Intern

April 2021 - May 2021

The role involved working on a plethora of Computer vision tasks and building functioning models based on those given tasks.

Pianalytix, remote— Machine Learning Research Intern

November 2020 - December 2020

The internship involves researching various machine learning topics and writing detailed research articles explaining them which were published later.

The Sparks Foundation, remote—Data Science Intern

October 2020 - November 2020

Resolving a set of challenging Data Science problems and working on data analysis on the given set of information.

SKILLS

- Python, Selenium Automation,
 Flask Backend Connectivity
- Machine Learning, Deep Learning (NN, CNN, RNN, R-CNN), Tensorflow, OpenCV, Keras
- Natural Language Processing
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript JQuery, ECMAScript,,Ajax, XML
- PHP, SQL (ORACLE, MYSQL, MARIA)
 Data warehousing
- Java, C, C++

PROJECTS

- Music Genre Classification And Comparing various algorithms -Machine Learning, Flask, HTLM, CSS
- Indian Sign Language Translator

Argyle HR Solutions Pvt Ltd, Mumbai — Business Development *Intern* June 2019 - July 2019

A month-long internship including tasks like website management, data handling and client interaction.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Introduction to TensorFlow for Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, and Deep Learning Coursera
- Natural Language Processing in Vectorized Models Coursera
- Convolutional Neural Networks in Python Udemy
- Automate the Boring Stuff with Python Programming Udemy
- Image Classification with CNNs using Keras Coursera
- HTML, CSS, and Javascript for Web Developers Coursera
- Building Basic General Adversarial Networks
- Using Python to Access Web Data Coursera
- Javascript SoloLearn
- PHP SoloLearn
- MATLAB Mathworks training course

OTHER COURSES

- Deep Learning Specialization Coursera [4 audit courses]
- Natural Language Processing Specialization [4 audit courses]
- Natural Language Processing in Tensorflow [audit course]
- Convolution Neural Networks in Tensorflow [audit course]

CLUBS

Rotaract Club Of Bombay Powai (Community Service), Mumbai

- President (2021-)
- Community Service Director & Sergeant-At-Arms (2020-2021)
- General Body Member (2019-2020)

August 2019 - Present

It is a community-based club that involves various large scale projects, community service, professional development, club service and other various events.

TSEC CodeCell (Technical), Mumbai

— Jr. Committee Member

October 2019 - March 2020

Work included conducting a hackathon, working on technical questions for an event and marketing which included finding potential sponsors.

- (internship) NLP, Python
- Online KYC Verification System CNN, ML, Flask, HTML CSS JS
- E-commerce Aggregator Selenium Automation Python
- Movie Recommendation System (Content-based filtering) -Python
- Written Published Articles on –
 Decision Tree, OpenCV, Text
 Summarization, Autocorrect using
 NLP
- Automated Episode Player Selenium Automation Python
- User-NGO platform (Ongoing) 'The WireUs' - Html CSS JS Django
- Twitter Sentiment Analysis NLP in Python
- A Movie Booking System Java
- Cats VS Dogs CNN Tensorflow
- Personalized Streaming List maintainer with User Authentication
 - HTML CSS JS PHP MySQL

Research Papers

Musical Genre Classification comparative study on various ML models, 2021 International Journal for Research in Applied Science and Engineering Technology(IJRASET)]

Sentimental Analysis comparative study on various DL and ML approaches [eta 1 month]

Indian Sign Language Grammatical Representation and NLP translation [eta 1.5 months]

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH, HINDI